Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Health Serials TAM.784
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Health Serials
1936-2004
1980-1999
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.784
1.6 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Health Serials contains over 50 titles on physical and mental health issues, medical professionals, and social and political issues related to health in the United States and other countries. The collection dates between 1936 and 2004, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1980s through the 1990s.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to health drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Health Serials contains over 50 titles on physical and mental health issues, medical professionals, and social and political issues related to health in the United States (US), Canada, Germany, Sweden, and the United Kingdom. The collection dates between 1936 and 2004, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1980s through the 1990s. Topics include hunger and food assistance programs in the US, end of life care, national health insurance, and HIV and AIDS. The collection also includes serials published by associations of nurses, doctors, therapists, and other professionals.
Serials (publications); Mental health -- United States.; Medical personnel -- United States.; Food security.; Health insurance -- United States.
- Achoo!: Gesundheit Institute, Alexandria, VA, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- American Journal of Socialized Medicine: Medical League for Socialized Medicine, Brooklyn, NY, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- AmFAR Newsletter: American Foundation for AIDS Research, New York, NY, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ASH Smoking and Health Review: Action on Smoking and Health, Washington, DC, 1982-1995 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
- Beginnings: American Holistic Nurses' Association, Springfield, MO, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bulletin: Physicians Forum, New York, NY, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Calendar: New York Counties Registered Nurses Association, Inc./District 13 of the New York State Nurses Association, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Cassandra:, Williamsville, NY, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- CCNHS: Special Conference Report: Chicago Coalition for a National Health Service, Chicago, IL, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Choice in Dying News: Choice in Dying, New York, NY, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Choices: Choice in Dying, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3, Box 2, Folder 1)
- Chronicle: Center for the Study of the History of Nursing, Philadelphia, PA, 1991-2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- CINAHL News: Cumulative Index to Nursing & Allied Health Literature, Glendale, CA, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- CIR (Committee of Interns and Residents) News: Committee of Interns and Residents, New York, NY, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Committee of Interns & Residents Bulletin:, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Community Health News: Central Seattle Community Health Centers, Seattle, WA, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Dendron: Clearinghouse on Human Rights & Psychiatry, Eugene, OR, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Die Gesetzliche Kranken-Versicherung: Bundesministerium fur Gesundheit, Bonn, Germany, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Drug Policy Letter: Drug Policy Foundation, Washington, DC, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
- Exchange: Exchange, Milwaukee, WI, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Food First Action Alert: Institute for Food & Development Policy, Oakland, CA, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Food First News: Food First News, San Francisco, CA, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Food Paper: The Development Education Centre, Toronto, Canada, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Gray Panther Network: Age and Youth in Action: Gray Panther Network, Philadelphia, Pa., 1975-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Group Health: Group Health Association-Group Health Mutual, Inc., St. Paul, MN, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Health Care Activist: Democratic Socialists of America, New York, NY, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Health Liberation News: Medical Committee for Human Rights, New York, NY, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Health Question: New American Movement, Berkeley, CA, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- INFACT News: INFACT, Minneapolis, MN, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- International Year of the Child: International Year of the Child 1979, Seattle, WA (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Links Health and Development Report: National Central America Health Rights Network, New York, NY, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Linus Pauling Institute of Science and Medicine Newsletter: Linus Pauling Institute of Science and Medicine, Palo Alto, CA, 1984-1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Madness Network News: MNN, San Francisco, CA, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Mealey's Litigation Report: Asbestos: LexisNexis, King of Prussia, PA, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
- NEHW Health Watch: Nurses' Environmental Health Watch, Somerville, MA, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Network: Family Health International, Piedmont, NC, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- News and Information from: SEMCOSH: Southeast Michigan Coalition on Occupational Safety and Health, Detroit, MI, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- News from the Forum: Physicians Forum, New York, NY, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- NSNA News: National Student Nurses' Association, New York, NY, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- NY City Crisis Center Newsletter: NY City Crisis Center, New York, NY, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Old Age Security: Report of the Proceedings of the Second National Conference on Old Age Security: American Association for Old Age Security, New York, NY, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- People's Health: Fritzi Englestein Free People's Health Center, Chicago, IL, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Peoples Health Action Forum: Peoples Health Action, Detroit, MI, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- PHNP Newsletter: Physicians for a National Health Program, Chicago, IL, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Phoenix: Citizens for the Improvement of Nursing Homes, Seattle, WA, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Pulse: PULSE Collective, New York, NY, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Radical Therapist: Radical Therapist, Inc., West Sommerville, MA, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Radical Therapist: Radical Therapist, Inc., Minot, ND, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Reports: Committee on Preventative Psychiatry of the Group for the Advancement of Psychiatry, Topeka, KS, 1951-1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Safety/Health Program Newsletter: Central Labor Rehabilitation Council of New York, New York, NY, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- SCAPHA News: Socialist Cacus of the American Public Health Association, Brooklyn, NY, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- SCAPHA News: Socialist Caucus of the American Public Health Association, Chicago, IL, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Self & Society Special Issue: Self and Society, London, England, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Self and Society: British Association for Humanistic Psychology, London, England, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Senior Citizens News: National Council of Senior Citizens, Washington, D.C., 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Truth: United Front Against Racism and Capitalism-Imperialism, New York, NY, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Update: Second Harvest, Chicago, IL, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Working Environment: Foreningen For Arbetarskydd Kungsholms Hamnplan, Stockholm, Sweden, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- ZPG Reporter: Zero Population Growth, Inc., Washington, DC, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)